<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Correspondence on Bogstandard</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/bogstandard/tags/correspondence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Correspondence on Bogstandard</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/bogstandard/tags/correspondence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analogue Correspondence Card Games</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bogstandard/posts/analogue-correspondence-card-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bogstandard/posts/analogue-correspondence-card-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To play a card game like poker by correspondence would require the decks to be exactly the same sequence in both locations similar to correspondence chess where the boards must be exactly the same states in both locations. (For simplicity I am speaking on the assumption of two players, but for &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; players the rule remains.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However unlike chess where the players can openly see the state of the board, the players in a card game like poker must be unaware of the state of the deck. This makes things trickier, and so both players must perform a shared seeded blind shuffle of their decks, the goal being to have both shuffle their decks fairly but result in the same unknown sequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correspondence Poker by Seeded Random</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bogstandard/posts/correspondence-poker-by-seeded-random/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bogstandard/posts/correspondence-poker-by-seeded-random/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoy &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Correspondence_chess&#34;&gt;correspondence chess&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plaintext&#34;&gt;plaintext&lt;/a&gt; computing, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stateless_protocol&#34;&gt;stateless APIs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jamstack&#34;&gt;Jamstack&lt;/a&gt;, and I also enjoy poker; so a while back I created a means of playing poker by correspondence via linked webpages: &lt;a href=&#34;https://bogstandard.github.io/plaintext-poker/&#34;&gt;Plaintext-Poker&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bogstandard/plaintext-poker&#34;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This utilises a seeded random (actually Java’s Random ported to Javascript!) to ensure that players stay on the same deck and same game state without any memory being used anywhere. It does this in a stateless fashion by using the seed to perform the exact same previous actions for each stage, given the seed via the URL, with a player number, the number of players and the game stage also included.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
