<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Military on Bogstandard</title>
    <link>https://bogstandard.github.io/bogstandard/tags/military/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Military on Bogstandard</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bogstandard.github.io/bogstandard/tags/military/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Silver&#39;s Brief Instructions (1/?)</title>
      <link>https://bogstandard.github.io/bogstandard/posts/on-george-silvers-brief-instructions-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bogstandard.github.io/bogstandard/posts/on-george-silvers-brief-instructions-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bogstandard.github.io/bogstandard/posts/on-george-silvers-brief-instructions-i/Suites_d&#39;un_bal_masqu%C3%A9_-_G%C3%A9r%C3%B4me_-_Mus%C3%A9e_Cond%C3%A9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Suites d&amp;rsquo;un bal masqué by Gérôme Jean Leon&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;The Duel After the Masquerade by Gérôme Jean Leon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everything written in this article is done using George Silver&amp;rsquo;s Brief Instructions as the single source, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pbm.com/~lindahl/brief.html&#34;&gt;Greg Lindahl&amp;rsquo;s transcription&lt;/a&gt; used for understandable quotes, but you can view a copy of the text that&amp;rsquo;s nearer to the original on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/worksgeorgesilv00mattgoog/page/n183/mode/2up&#34;&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt; if you enjoy squinting and headaches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m deliberately ignoring the original Paradoxes of Defense here, it&amp;rsquo;s a chore to read, and an angry embarrassing mess. Like Marcion rejecting the Old Testament, followers of Silver should be lauding the clear, rules-based methodology of the later Brief Instructions and shunning of the polemic Paradoxes of Defense.  Brief Instructions existing at all hints that even Silver understood his original work was pretty awful and his later adoption of manualistic style hints that he knew also the original was rubbish for teaching anything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fencing Masks for U.S. Infantry &amp; Cavalry, circa 1919</title>
      <link>https://bogstandard.github.io/bogstandard/posts/fencing-masks-circa-1919/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bogstandard.github.io/bogstandard/posts/fencing-masks-circa-1919/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometime shortly before January 24, 1919, the A.G. Spalding Brothers Company developed fencing masks for the U.S. Government. Two masks are recorded in the National Archives, one for infantry and one cavalry, a front and side view is presented for each.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Curiously it is the cavalry mask which bears the best resemblance to the modern fencing masks we’re familiar with nowadays. It also offers the best protection, while contrastingly the infantry mask offers better visual fidelity – at expense of eye cover.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
